Uh
Hello Hello
Hello.
Hello, Costa Ris.
How are you?
I'm doing good.
I was testing out the audio setup.
Okay.
I think I just started my Discord.
That's fine.
Okay.
Yes, I'm online.
Oh, yes.
Yes.
Sorry.
Um, I actually didn't know which one you were going to use.
So I sent you messages on all three.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Thanks for that.
My desktop Discord client I did not check.
Okay.
So we
The storyline is pretty interesting, Costa.
That's why I've just been waiting to play it again.
we have the phone hill.
I've been bugging you like a couple of times.
Dude, I'm enjoying it too.
Yeah, okay.
If I wasn't.
Trust me, I don't play things I don't find interesting.
Oh.
I'm a finished tuned.
Okay, so when we last left our Noble Adventures, they had just entered the Stone Hill Tavern.
Yes.
And they were planning to spend the night before they headed off to go fight to go rescue their patron, Gundren Rockseeker.
Who everybody hopes is still alive.
Of course, he might not be, in which case it's kind of sad.
And, you know, your decision to come and spend the night at the tavern may cost him his life, but, you know, such is the brakes.
You know, such are the choices of adventures.
You know, playing God, playing God, you know, kind of thing.
Hope he's alive.
Hopefully he's still alive.
Alright.
So.
Let me just get rid of this one.
Delete.
Okay.
I need to do
all.
Alright.
Okay.
So you are in the Stonehill Tavern.
Alright.
Okay.
Let's place the party.
You can see it, I hope.
The party.
Yes, I can see it inside the taverns.
Alright, so.
Alright, so you're in the Stone Hill.
That seems a bit.
About the same right size.
Alright.
Okay.
Pretty big tavern.
So this is the Stonehill Tavern.
And who else?
Who is in the Stone Hill Tavern?
The area behind, you know, so this is the main tavern area.
The thing on the left that you could see is the second floor.
Alright, the other half of the map?
Yeah, this is the second floor.
Did you mark something?
I cannot.
So, no, I just did it now.
Can you see it?
No, I don't see any mark from the map.
You should see.
What map are you looking at?
What do you see on the map right now?
Um, okay, hold on.
Let me share my screen.
Ah, you're not zooming out.
I did zoom out.
Oh, I just, okay, zoom out all the way?
Yes.
Alright, so here, let me show you.
Show, share, share your screen.
Okay.
This is what I'm seeing.
Yeah, scroll to the right.
Oh, oh, all the way.
Okay.
That's black.
Yes, that's the second floor.
Okay, cool.
Yes, okay.
So all I could see was this.
So you can see the first floor.
Alright, now let me just drop the characters.
Okay.
So there is a commoner.
Alright.
So I'm going to drop the the NPCs you can interact with.
Toblin Stonehill owner.
Okay.
A few people at the farm.
Alrighty.
So the place, it's in the middle of the day, so it's you know, there's not many people here today.
Such a large place, it's kind of confusing that there aren't that many people here.
But so be it.
And let me just read this.
The common room is warm but watchful.
Everyone has heard a wagon come in without Gundren Rockseeker.
A few local pretend not to stare.
Others are waiting to see whether you are brave, dangerous, or merely passing through.
Toblin approaches you with some forced hospitality.
Rooms are ready.
Hot stew if you want it.
And if you're Gundren Rockseeker's friends, well, folk here, we all want to know what you know.
He's a broad-shouldered young human man with sandy hair, tired blue eyes, and rolled-up sleeves dusted with flour and hearthash.
He smiles easily, but keeps glancing to the door whenever voices rise.
Okay.
So you can sort of ask him about rumors, stories.
I mean, it's up to you, or you can like sit down to.
The person who approached is the tuck or.
It's Toblin.
Sorry.
I should have.
Yeah.
Let me just make sure.
Sorry.
I was.
If you don't mind, stop sharing, because I keep thinking I'm looking at it.
Okay.
Okay, that's perfect.
Alright.
So, um.
Okay.
Well, thank you for having us tonight.
Tell us more about how Gundren Rockseeker was.
Like, what were his times of visit?
Or, you know, how was he related to you?
Well, he's not related to me, but he brought business.
He was a merchant.
He was a good man.
And his brother did good business here.
So, you know, and losing somebody is always, you know, we always care about our people.
Well, yeah, let's not make any assumptions.
We still have not lost him.
I'm going to bring him back.
Oh, well, that's wonderful to hear.
That is.
That is wonderful to hear.
Alright.
So, were there any threats for him that you knew of?
Did he have any enemies that you know?
Was he involved in any fights here?
Sorry, too many questions at the same time.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, that's fine.
You're trying to.
I just need to figure out.
Okay, so ask your question.
Did he have any enemies or was he involved in any fights here before?
Toblin says, look, I don't like trouble, and I don't want trouble, so why don't you grab a table, and Elsa will come and feed you?
Okay.
Alright.
So grab a table.
Yeah, he goes, like, you know, this.
He pauses and turns to you and says, what does he say?
He says, well, hold on.
He says, I don't like trouble in my common room.
Trumblin Fandalin has a habit of walking home with you.
So you get the impression that he's the kind of guy who's like, you definitely get a vibe that there is trouble in Vandalin.
Yes.
Okay.
Right.
And he doesn't want to.
So he goes.
Right.
Elsa comes out and says, shouts, grab a table or pick a stool on the bar.
So where would you like to go?
I would go to the bar table because that's where I feel most conversations might have.
Alright, so you're going to go to the bar.
Okay.
She's a dwarf bartender, sharp-eyed.
She's a compact dwarf woman with copper-brown skin, thick black braids pinned beneath a head kerchief, and forearms strung from hauling casks.
Her dark eyes miss nothing, and she polishes mugs like she's interrogating them.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I'll ask her to get her something to drink.
Oh, she says, well, that is very kind of you.
That is very, very kind of you.
And let me just do something here.
That is very kind of you.
And she pours beer and pours you a beer.
Let me see.
Okay, and so she goes, are you from Fan?
Did you guys just come in?
You guys just came in from Vandalin, right?
Yes.
Yeah, this is Fandelin, but we...
No, sorry, Never Winter, Never Winter.
Sorry.
She goes, well, well, well, my sister.
My sister is a scholar in the city of Neverwinter.
And you can see she's very, very proud of it.
Vera recognizes the name.
Oh, do you know her sister, Vera?
Vera says, no, but I think my mentor, Professor Oren Voss, knew her.
So that's his name.
But you said your professor disappeared here, right?
She goes, yeah, well, he came to Fandalin shortly before Vandis vanishing.
He believed that there were black stone fragments that were part of some large obelisk.
You see this blue candle?
It reacted to obelisk fragments and certain kinds of psionic magic.
He feared the obelisk was connected to minds, memory, and transformation.
And what he told me was never let anyone assemble the fragments.
Okay.
I don't know what to make of that information, but I'm thinking.
I mean, but part of it, so as you look at, you kind of like absorb this information, right?
Yes, yes.
She goes, I just want to know that he wasn't losing his mind.
I mean, it sounds so crazy, doesn't it?
It does.
It does, yes.
And he was such a good man, and I don't want...
It has to not be that he was losing his mind.
When we were on our way to Fandalin, something similar happened to me when we hit a rock.
I noticed, like, I believe I saw a shadow of an obelisk or something.
So you say that, right, out loud?
I didn't say that.
I say that out to Vera.
Okay.
We say that to Vera.
Yeah, yeah.
I mean, the others who are at the bar table then.
Alright.
Pip Thistlewick.
Pip Thistlewick says.
Let's see, where is it now?
Looking for something for some nibs.
Pip Thistlewick says, I heard a whisper that said, returned.
Right?
Okay.
And Sister Maela Dawnforge says, really?
Because I felt a brief chill in my holy symbol.
Like right now?
No, no, no, no.
Oh, okay.
I just thought I was going crazy.
So something is strange here then.
I didn't hear of any incidents like these before.
I'm going to inspect them.
You're asking Elsa, right?
Elsa, yes.
She goes, she turns to Vera and Hugh and says, she looks at Vera and says, you're not the first bookish sort to come here looking for old stones.
And yes, I've seen many people.
In fact, my sister is my sister.
And goes off and explains how her sister is this really important person who's thirty, and that she's very proud of her and that she became the pride of the family.
Right?
She also says, you know, Darren Edermath, the orchard keeper, is a former adventurer.
He might have more information about this place.
Interesting.
Where is he?
What does he do?
Where can I find Darren?
And I will show you on the adventure map.
You will find him.
Okay, so the orchard is here.
Here being.
I can see it on my map, but you can't see it on yours.
Town green shrine of luck stone and turn.
Can you see it?
Endermath Orchard?
Trying to find.
Yes, yes.
Edermath Orchard, yes.
Edermath Orchard.
Alright.
She goes, well, if you're interested in adventure, he might know something, but if you ask me, I think you should just wait for my sister and she'll figure everything out because she's that kind of person.
She's really smart, you know.
She got and proceeds to explain how she got accepted to the right universities and the right scholars and is all the rage of the family.
You can tell that she's very proud of her sister.
Seems like you're proud of your sister.
I'm sure she is a good person and a scholar.
Yes, yes, she is.
Okay.
Then I'm going to just stand up and.
Oh, wait, hold on.
He goes, hold on, before he goes out, she goes, Darren Edermath is in a retired drow adventurer.
He's like over 500 years old and has worked as a marshal and herald for many years in the lands of the dragon coast, far to the south.
He's a good guy that you should go talk to.
And he's heard stories from all over.
And if there's anything that you want to know about this place, I'm sure he knows about it.
Okay.
Alright.
Well, thank you also for the information.
You seem like a nice person.
Well, she goes, of course I'm a nice person, and you're a nice person for buying me a beer.
Thank you.
Then I'm going to stand up and lift my glass and say cheer just to get attention of other people in the bar.
I see there are some other NPCs who I still have not interacted.
Right.
Yeah.
So, yeah, that's what I would do.
And then.
So Frida looks at you very nervously and quietly and angry, but not at you, but angry about something.
Okay.
So she's a Gnomish.
You look at her and she's a single, slight Gnomish woman with all silver-streaked hair, round spectacles, and a shawl of her own careful weaving.
Her fingers are always moving, twisting loose thread or wearing the edge of her sleeves.
She turns to you and says, Are you new here?
Yes, ma'am.
He goes, says, well, sit down.
And she orders, she barks like a matronly mother to have you sit down.
So I presume you grab chairs and sit down.
Okay.
I'm assuming.
You can tell me you don't.
Yeah, maybe you sit down, yes.
You do sit down.
Alright.
Okay.
So Freda says, I don't know what...
I heard you said that Gundren Rockseeker was missing.
Yes.
Well, you know, I know who's behind it.
Oh, that's interesting.
Can you tell us, please?
The Red Brands.
They're a gang of.
It's a Grant Game.
The Red Brands.
Red Brands?
Yes.
Right.
I want them gone, but I don't want my neighbors to get hurt.
And she goes.
What does the neighbors have to do with this?
She goes, well, I mean, I want them gone, but I don't want any of my neighbors hurt.
And she's looking at you like, you're not neighbors.
Therefore, if you were to get them gone and get heard, that would satisfy her two constraints.
Her goal and her constraint.
That is selfish, but okay.
Yes, yes.
She says, you know, she's got this small voice, but like this big resentment.
And then she goes, you know what I don't step out the red brands?
They bother everyone.
Everyone except Halia.
Makes you wonder whether they fear her, owe her, or both.
Who is Halia here?
Halia.
Oh, she goes, who's Halia?
Yeah.
Alright, let me just give you that information.
Halia.
She explains.
Alright.
Where are you?
She works at the Fandalin Miners Exchange.
Alright.
So, let me just make fancy.
So, Holly, apparently, she turns to you and says, If you're the kind of person who wants to find out who's a crook and who's a criminal and who's behind it all, I'd start there.
Alright, so the Fandalin Miner Exchange.
Minor Exchange, okay.
Alright.
Okay.
Do you want to go talk to the other two people?
Yes, yes.
I want to pretend to be drunk a little bit and then try to make a small talk with the other two people and the Stonehill, Tuck Stonehill.
Pardon me?
Tuck Stonehill, the son of the owner?
You want to go talk to him?
No, I have not spoken to these three people, so.
Alright, well, Tuck is a nine-year-old boy, and he kind of approaches you.
He's got a mop of sandy hair, a missing front tooth, and knees scuffed from climbing things.
He was told not to climb.
He tries to stand like a guard when watching.
He goes, Oh, hey, I want to tell you something.
Right.
What's up, Limkin?
He said, Karp saw a tunnel, a real one, but his ma said to not talk about it because the red cloaks nearly caught him.
Wait, who saw the tunnel?
He goes, Karp, my friend.
Oh, okay.
Karp!
Karp, you know, Karp.
Well, Karp is Karp Alderleaf.
His ma, he's my good friend, and he said he saw a tunnel that goes into the woods, and that, you know, but his ma said to not go there because that's where the red cloaks are.
Do you know where the tunnel is?
He goes, oh, yeah, I could totally show you.
And you don't know if he can, or he's going to get his friend to show it, but yes, you could get him to show it to you.
Okay.
We can do that sometime.
Thanks for that.
Alright.
He goes.
And he goes, you know, he then pauses to you, says, you know, you're going after Gundren Rockseeker, right?
Yes.
Good.
People who get taken don't always come back.
You're going to get him, right?
Yes.
Has anyone else got taken before?
Like Gundren Rockseeker?
Yes.
Many people.
Wow.
That's sad.
Right.
Okay.
Alright, so the next person is Narth.
North, yes.
He's an older human man with weathered skin, a stooped back, and pale eyes that linger on windows, doorways, and bad omens.
He smells faintly of hay, rain, and pipe smoke.
He looks at you and goes.
He looks at Sister Maela Dawnforge and says, You're temple folk, aren't you?
Sister Maela Dawnforge says, Yes.
Well, Sister Garrel came back, limping and pale.
Wouldn't say from where.
Folks who serve gods learn when not to speak, I suppose.
And then he pauses.
Maybe she'll talk to you before she talks to the rest of us.
I'm kind of worried about her, and it would be really kind if you were to go talk to her.
She won't talk to us because she's always trying to protect us, but maybe you can go find out what's going on.
Yeah, yeah, I can definitely find out if she's willing to talk to me.
I can put a cry.
Thank you for that.
And then Lanar sort of stands up and goes.
You notice he's a lean human with sunken cheeks, a dusty gray beard, and cracked hands permanently stained by ore and lampsuit.
His cap sits crooked and he talks with a mug lifted halfway to his mouth.
He speaks loudly, right?
And he goes, Everybody here doesn't really want to talk with the issues.
Goblins, bandits, orcs, Red Bander, Red Brands, doesn't matter what they use.
Roads aren't safe, and Harbin Wester is still hiding behind notices and wax seals.
You want to ask who's Harbin Wester?
Who's Harbin Western?
He is the Town Master.
Useless, he is the Town Master.
Oh my god, is he useless?
He's like, he's done nothing.
He has done nothing.
Well, and thank God you folks have come here.
Pauses and says, if you ask me, somebody has to deal with why the roads aren't safe.
I mean, poor Gundren Rockseeker was captured and you were at.
Were you attacked?
No, yelling.
No, yes, yes, we were attacked.
Yes.
Why attacked him?
We were attacked by the goblins.
On the way to the fountain.
Wait, why are you going to give me?
Wait, hold on.
Everybody died.
TPK, all new characters.
My wife's saying everybody died, TPK.
There's only one person.
Yeah, it's a corker by now.
That's not DD.
Yes, it is.
Alright.
So.
Do you want a beer?
I'd love one, yes.
Okay, so the only thing that you might want to do is like go back to Toblin and ask him about the Red Brands.
Toblin?
Where's the bad?
The guy.
He's at the table, back at the table.
Okay.
Right, not Toblin, you know, he's the owner of the place, right?
Yes.
Sorry, Toblin is sort of Toblin's over here.
Toblin was at the bar, yes.
Yeah, right.
So, and Tuck.
Go back to the top.
Go back to him?
Yes.
Thank you.
Alright.
Do you want to ask him?
You now learn, like, you know, there's apparently these red brands, there's goblins, there's the mayor, there's a cleric that was wounded.
Like, yeah, I'm going to ask him, hey, Toblin, I've been hearing about the red brands and attacks on the way, and about the town master and Darren.
What's going on?
It looks like everything is weird in this town.
Like, can you care to tell me?
Might help us in finding Gundran safe and sound.
Okay, look.
Red Brands killed a man in the street, broad daylight.
Then his wife and children vanished.
So forgive me if I lower my voice.
He pauses.
They drink at the sleeping.
They drink at the sleep.
Elsewhere and talk if you want.
You don't feel safe talking in the hallway.
No, he goes, he turns around.
These are all friends, but I don't want to talk too loudly.
And he goes.
But he does tell you that he tells you the name of the person who was murdered.
Tell Dendar.
And that the Red Brands drink at the Sleeping Giant.
Wait, what?
The Red Brands drink at the Sleeping Giant?
Yes.
Okay.
What's the Sleeping Giant?
That's it.
Yes, and so he tells you where it is.
So let me just show you where it is on the map.
The Sleeping Giant.
Sleeping Giant.
Also, pretty much they are in the town, like almost outside of the town, a little bit.
Well, I mean, this is a small town, right?
And so this distance here is like, I don't know, 200 feet.
Right, right, okay.
So Sleeping Giant is.
You can ask him about the Sleeping Giant.
So are the Red Brands like bandits?
Alright, can you see it?
Or are they like, you know, do they have any magical powers?
Do they have it?
He goes, they're just tough guys.
Okay.
They're just tough guys who have managed to come into our small town and to think that they run the place.
And nobody has stood up to them.
That's interesting.
Why hasn't Darren stepped up?
He seems to.
I heard that he seems to be an adventure.
And he turns and says, well, you may not know this, but most adventurers die.
And the only ones that live are the ones that quit while they're ahead.
Okay.
Makes sense.
Not everybody is.
Most adventurers either die or quit.
So tell me a little more about the sleeping giant.
What was it?
Is it like an inn or have they occupied it like this?
Okay, so great question.
Alright, so this is a rundown tap house.
It's a dirty, it's a dirty, dangerous watering hole at the end of Fandolan's main street.
It is free quite it, and he goes, that's where the red brands hang out.
Now, as you're pausing here, you realize this is a frontier town, right?
Yep.
Oh, yes.
You're from India.
Why would you know that?
Okay, so ethnicity.
So, a common trope in Dungeons and Dragons is the idea of a town that is at the edge of civilization.
Oh, I see.
Okay.
And so towns that are at the edge of civilization are kind of like, have you seen Star Wars?
Yes, yes.
Moss Isley.
I don't remember it.
That's where Luke Skywalker tries, says where Obi-Wan Kenobi says, Sky villainy.
That's why.
It's like almost a beaten-down town, kind of thing, right?
Well, it's not beaten down, but it's kind of like the central authorities don't have much power.
How about I put it that way?
Okay, okay.
Right, so I don't know, like, I'm sure in India there are towns where the central authorities have left the towns to fend for themselves.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right?
And in those towns, as you could imagine, the criminal element thrives.
Yes, okay.
Right?
And so that's the way to think about the Red Brands.
Okay, okay.
This is a town which is at the limits of the central government's power.
And as a result, gangs emerge.
And what you've clearly gathered is the Red Brands are one of those gangs.
Right.
Yeah.
Right?
And this is kind of normal.
Like, as someone who you would expect this kind of thing.
Like, for all you know, they're just a bunch of people.
Like, you don't know why they killed who they killed.
Maybe that guy pissed them off.
Maybe that guy was a member of the gang.
My point is, you don't actually know who or what they are.
You just know that some people don't like this gang.
Right.
Okay.
Yeah.
I get a sense of it.
Like, Vegas was once upon a time dictated by the gangsters.
Right.
So if you think of it that way.
Yeah.
Does that make sense?
Yes.
Got it.
All right.
So yeah.
So that's the way to think about it.
All right.
And so, you know, so then that's it for today.
You wake up in the morning, and I presume you're going to head up back to go find out what the heck happened to Gundren?
Yeah.
So.
Or you want to go talk to Halia, or what do you want to do?
Don't forget.
Before.
Let's go.
Go ahead.
Yeah.
So what do you want to do?
Do you want to, like, this morning.
So you're saying like every minute I spend in this town is going to cost his life.
That's what people are telling you.
But I do need some information, right?
So I wanted to talk to Darren.
I wanted to talk to Halia.
All right.
So you want to go talk to Darren?
Yeah, real quick.
You know, maybe one hour or two hours before I start.
All right.
You know, who knows?
Maybe you'll learn something useful, right?
Yes.
Information is found.
All right.
So.
Okay.
So you see him.
Darren is well over 500 years old.
He's worked as a marshal and herald for many years in the lands of the Dragon Coast, part of the South.
Upon retiring, he returned to Neverwinter the region in his original home.
Wait, he's 500 years old?
Yeah, they're elves.
They live that long.
Alright.
Okay.
So let me just get, I need to get a commoner.
He definitely has that look of somebody who's seen it all, done it all, but is very happy to see you.
He goes, when he sees you, he goes, why?
Are you adventurers?
Not exactly, but we fall in that category.
Wow.
Maybe then Pip Thistlewick might step in and try to show off.
Pip Thistlewick goes, we are absolutely adventurers.
He stands, I, and he proceeds to explain how I came to Fandalan because I believe that it's important for us to do good, and because I know there's always somebody, there's always a community that needs a man who's got a good sword arm.
Okay.
Darran looks at him and says, Pip Thistlewick, you are my kind of man.
Pip Thistlewick like smiles profusely.
Like, obviously, the guy's got issues where he's being recognized.
He's being recognized.
He's like, I'm.
He goes.
He goes, well, I've got to tell you something, Pip Thistlewick.
I am very concerned about those Red Brands, and I'd like to see a group of heroes just like you guys teach those ruffians a lesson.
I mean, someone's got to take a stand against their leader.
Yeah, so needs to take a stand.
That's what I said.
Someone that hasn't taken a stand.
Oh, needs to take a stand.
Okay.
Yeah.
His name's Glastaff.
Glastaff.
Yeah, Glastaff.
Okay.
One word.
He goes, anyway, the Red Brands, let me just tell you some things I've learned.
I keep an eye out on things.
I was once a marshal, so I know how to keep track of criminals and ruffians.
That's interesting.
Skill.
Well, he goes, The Red Brands hang around the Sleeping Giant Tap House, but I do know where their safe house is.
Where is it?
It's under Tressender Manor.
You should see it over here.
Do you see it?
It's past the Sleeping Giant.
Yes, yes.
You see this orange yellow dot here?
Yes, rundown house.
Yes.
He goes, that's where their safe house is.
What's it called?
Tressender Manor.
Okay.
Alright?
Right.
Okay.
Oh, Tressender.
Then.
Do you know how many of the Red Brands are there?
How many are there?
At the Tressender Manor.
Somewhere between 3 and 10.
That's a huge range.
You know, I'm saying I don't know the exact number, so I'm telling you, as Castatus, between 3 and 10, he would tell you the exact number.
It would take me a while to go figure it out.
Does that make sense?
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
Then he pauses and says, Well, Pip Thistlewick, I like you.
Pip Thistlewick goes, yes?
And I got a problem that I think you should deal with.
I've heard that there are prospectors in the hills northwest of Fandalin that someone is digging in the ruins known as the Old Owlwell.
And apparently, several prospectors have been reported being chased from the area by foul undead.
Okay, because you may not know what undead are, undead are creatures that have been.
So in Dungeons and Dragons, there are creatures who aren't dead and aren't alive.
They've been basically reanimated.
So zombies, vampires, ghouls, ghasts, whites, all of that.
Alright?
He goes, now, I need to tell you, it's a couple days' march northeast of Fandalin.
Find out who's there and what they're doing.
Now, I know those ruins are an old watchtower of an ancient magical empire known as Nethril.
And I'm worried that there's some dangerous magic that might be there.
Now, you can go there and ensure there's no threat to the town brewing at Old Well.
I'm willing to give you some boots of striding and springing.
He goes, it came in handy when I was an adventure, but I'm out of that.
I'm out of the game.
So I'd be willing to give them if you were to do such a good turn for the town.
Well, I would do it, but first I guess we have to go back find our friend.
Well, yes, you should.
Yes, well, he goes, yes, you should.
He pauses and goes, wait, you're talking to me instead of going to go find Gundren?
Shame on you.
You should go now.
Oh, okay.
That seems to be important.
Okay.
Pip Thistlewick goes, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
We just thought we'd get more information.
Pip Thistlewick, I'm not going to hold this against you, but you know, it's important to get information, and then it's important to do the right thing.
And, you know, the right thing is for you to go and find it and go and rescue Gundren.
Yes, no, I'm still thinking if I should go talk to Halia or just head to.
It's up to you, man.
It's up to you.
It's a tough choice.
Okay.
The pressure.
I'll take a leap of faith, just pray at the Shrine of Luck and then head to the Tribo Trail.
You're going to go to the Shrine of Luck?
Yeah, just for a minute, pray to the guard and then head out to the adventure, hoping the information from Halia is irrelevant.
Alright.
Let me see.
Alrighty.
Fandolin's only temple, this small shrine, is made of stones taken from the nearby ruins.
It is dedicated to Timora, the god of good luck and good fortune.
The shrine is in the care of a scholarly acolyte.
She's a Zalis young elf.
Shigerla looks at you.
She kind of.
It's kind of weird.
She looks at you and goes, Well, I see you're come to pray at the Shrine of Luck.
And to Timora.
And then she looks you over and says, What are you.
So she pauses and says, Are you the guys who came in from town where Gunther was missing?
Yes.
We are actually trying to find him.
Oh, well, you know, you should probably.
I don't know where he is, but you should go find him.
And, you know, may Tamora's blessing be upon you.
And when you find him and come back, come by.
I think I have another job for you.
Okay, sure.
Okay.
So.
Right.
Okay.
So we'll head out.
Yes.
She's, you know, she's not.
She's definitely got the.
You definitely get the vibe of I better not.
She's not going to give you any more quests until you go and deal.
Yeah.
All right.
Until you go and deal with this.
Alright.
So you head back to where the goblin ambush was.
Right.
And you take, I presume, the goblin trail, correct?
Yes, yes.
The goblin trails of two humans.
Direct.
Right.
Alright.
Okay, so one question.
In this game, there are side quests as well.
Yes.
Okay.
Yes, you want to go on the side quests.
No, I'll finish this main one first.
Wait, can we actually go to the side quest once we finish the main one?
Yes.
Well, okay, so no, the thing is, like.
So let me explain to you how the game works.
You have to accumulate experience points and treasure.
Treasure as in the coins.
Yes.
And so the reason you go on the side quests is to get coins.
Coins and treasure and magic.
Okay.
And the other thing you go on the side quests is because a side quest might you don't actually know what is a main quest in a side quest.
Well, I mean, like here the main quest is like finding and getting back Gundren.
No, that's just that could be a side.
That could be a complete side quest for all you know.
Oh.
So let's suppose if I just jump on a side quest, hypothetically, Gundren might die.
Yes.
Okay.
Okay, no, I don't want to kill anyone, so I'll just push this.
No, no, no, it's like, you know, like, or not.
Right.
Yeah, there is a possibility.
Yes.
It's just that the reason you might want to go get him is that whoever has got him is trying to get information from him.
And at some point in time, they're going to decide they tried enough.
Does that make sense?
Yes.
And once they've decided they've tried enough, they might say, you know, whatever.
We're not going to try this anymore.
Right.
Okay.
All right.
Moki Doki.
Alright.
Okay.
Okay, so about 10 minutes after heading down the trail, are you searching for traps or just like walking blindly?
I'm assuming you're searching.
Now the downside of searching.
My screen is blank.
It's black and white.
That's fine.
You're currently walking in the woods.
Oh, okay.
So yeah, we'll be carefully walking step by step, not rushing through.
Okay, so you're kind of like.
So here's the...
Looking out for animals, objects, or some kind of.
Alright, Pip Thistlewick, who's in the lead?
Let's put Pip Thistlewick because he seems empowered after talking to Darran.
Alright, Pip Thistlewick.
Alright, so the one good thing about having Pip Thistlewick is Pip Thistlewick is really good at handling attacks, but he doesn't have the world's best perception.
Sorry, what?
Perception.
His passive perception isn't very good.
Oh, okay.
Well, then I think I should.
You can walk next to him.
Yeah, I can walk next to him and use my perception.
Alright.
What's your passive perception?
12.
Pips is 13.
Alright.
Okay.
Roll a saving throw.
A DC10.
You stumble on a hidden pit.
Alright, roll your dexterity saving throw.
Slash a dexterity.
Okay.
Your dexterity saving throw.
Yeah.
Alright.
You avoid falling into the pit.
Okay.
Alright.
You go another 10 minutes and you encounter a hidden snare.
Alright, now Pip Thistlewick needs to roll a DC10 dexterity saving throw.
So let me see what Pip Thistlewick's saving throw is.
Dexterity plus one.
Pip Thistlewick is caught up in the snare.
And he's flipped tight tied down and suspended 10 feet above the ground.
I presume one of you is going to try to lower him?
Yes.
I think Sister Maela should lower him, or should I?
Well, both of you can.
Okay.
I'll lower him first, and then what do I roll for that?
Yeah, you just lower him.
There's nothing to roll.
Alright.
I don't roll anything?
No, no, no.
Not in this case.
Okay.
I also made sure to have you see you should be able to now see where the old owl well is, which is the quest you were going on.
Right.
You may see it over here.
You saw it?
I see a blue.
Oh, yeah, okay.
Old well owl.
Yes.
Alright.
Okay.
We are going.
No, no, you're going towards.
You're following this trail north.
Alright.
After managing to avoid one of the two traps,
alrighty, we will go to the map.
Okay.
So you are the path leads you to the goblin's trail ends at a cave in a hillside five miles from the scene of the ambush.
A shallow stream flows from the cave mouth, which is screened by a dense briar and thickets.
A narrow, dry path leads onto the cave on the right side of the stream.
Alright, so this is the.
I'm just going to draw it here.
This is the.
See the blue line?
Yeah.
Alright, that's the narrow path.
Alright.
So now, are you going to just sort of...
Do you guys want to look around or do you want to just charge in boldly?
What do you guys want to do?
Try to peek around the narrow path to see.
Alright, so who's going to do Zenvon?
You're the one with the very high stealth, so you probably should do the peeking.
Go peek.
What do I roll?
Strength, dexterity.
The stealth.
Roll the D20 and you should see a stealth.
Click on that.
Wait a minute.
Stealth.
Yes, okay.
Would you roll?
Yay.
Okay, yeah.
So you come over there and you see two goblins, and what else do you see?
I see three.
Yeah, two goblins and one goblin boss.
On the east side of the stream that flows from the cavemouth, a small area of briar thickets has been hollowed out to form a lookout post.
Wooden plants flatten the briars and provide rooms for guards to be hidden and watch the area, including several goblins lurking there right now.
So what are my options?
Well, your options are to go back and tell your party that they need to stage an ambush.
Right.
Okay, okay, yes.
I was just thinking if I should start the fight, but it would be foolish.
Okay, so I'll go back.
Okay, you go back and you tell everybody what you saw.
Yes, I saw two goblins and one goblin boss roaming around, like patrolling there, trying to keep an eye.
So I think it's hard to get past them without taking them down.
Yeah.
I guess.
Just to be clear, you also notice that they are bored and inattentive, so you could probably surprise them.
Okay.
So it looks like they are just relaxing.
Maybe it's a good time to be silent and attack them, give them a surprise attack.
Pip Thistlewick says, I'm always ready to attack a goblin.
He pulls out his sword.
Veira goes.
I need all of you guys to be calm and silent.
Alright, okay.
So what do you want to do?
Do you want to go around the top?
Do you want to go through the little briars?
What do you want to do?
Yeah, I'm going to go around the same point where I saw them from.
Okay.
So, alright.
Alright.
Okay.
So, everybody, roll your stealth chucks.
Roll your stealth chuck.
Stealth.
I rolled mine.
Alright.
They are surprised.
So let's roll for initiative.
Should I roll or are you going to roll?
You need to roll for your guy.
Which one should I roll for the initiative?
Okay, yeah, there is one initiative, yeah.
No, that's intelligence.
Yeah, initiative.
I don't see.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, I found it, yes.
Alright, 13.
And the goblins.
Goblin water 21?
Okay.
Yeah, but they're surprised, so you get to go first.
Zenvon.
I am going to start with a crossbow because it's a surprise attack and I cannot be close to them.
You can, if you want.
I'll start with the crossbow.
Alright.
So the goblins have an armor class of 15.
Oh, so I'm a light armor.
So I roll a strength?
No.
If you go look, show me your character sheet and I'll tell you what the click on and do the share screen.
Okay.
Where's your DD?
Okay, so we'll scroll down on the right side, scroll down.
Scroll to the left.
So scroll to the swipe to the left.
Okay.
Could you go scroll back up?
Where are your attacks?
Let me.
Okay, there.
I see it now, yes.
Okay, so you click on your shortbow.
So you see that where that little arrow is on the left?
Yes.
You see all the way to the right.
Yeah, you click that and it rolls both your attack and your damage in one go.
Ouch.
12 shortbow pre-swing, eight shortbow, sneak attack, and five.
Yeah, you rolled a natural one, which is an automatic miss.
What is it miss?
Okay.
No, is it?
What did you roll?
Yes.
You rolled a...
Yep, you rolled a miss.
You missed.
Alright.
Pip.
So,
alright.
Where are we?
Okay.
So Pip goes, well, that sucks.
But he's like.
So are they surprised?
Are they alert right now?
Well, now they're surprised, which is why you get a free round to attack.
Alright.
So he rushes in.
He rushes in.
Pip attacks this guy over here.
And this is.
Okay, that's not good.
Sister Maela.
She casts a sacred flame.
And, okay, well, none of these attacks worked, but fortunately, Veyra says, well, that's what they have magic users for.
And she's coming from over there.
She points her magic missiles through the briars.
She comes over here and she fires her magic missiles at the big boss.
Actually, she fires one magic missile at everybody, so they each take three points of damage.
Okay.
And then this guy takes another three points of damage.
Alright, so now, okay, this guy wakes up.
Yeah, Veyra.
Then after she does that, moves over here.
Alright, so the goblin charges straight at Pip Thistlewick and swings his weapon.
And this is completely.
Zenvon, you're up again.
Yes, okay.
This is a good time to use your daggers.
Your sword and your short dagger.
Remember, you can attack twice with them.
Yes, yes, I have a dagger in the morning.
What did you roll?
You rolled a natural 20.
So you didn't just kill this guy.
You sent him...
Did you ever see the TV show, the game Final Combat?
Mortal Kombat, Mortal Kombat?
Yes, yes, I've seen KO.
Finish him!
Finish him.
Alright, Veyra, after she had that success, is going to say, I should save my spells.
She's going to fire a firebolt.
It's a hit.
Yay.
She's a hit.
And it's five points of damage.
And so the other goblin dies.
Alrighty.
Yeah.
Alright, so the other goblin.
We have a boss.
Right.
And the boss sort of goes.
And Veyra would not be here.
She would know.
So, Sister Maela comes charging at you and swings at Pip Thistlewick.
Swings at Pip Thistlewick?
Yes, he does.
Oh, yeah, this guy.
Okay.
Yes.
An Irk swings at Pip Thistlewick goes and he misses completely.
Alright.
Let me just make sure I got this guy.
Okay, actually attacks twice with his scimitar.
He misses the first attack.
And let me see what Pip Thistlewick's armor clause is.
And Pip Thistlewick's Armor Clause is.
Ah, misses the second time as well.
Alrighty.
So now it's Pip Thistlewick's turn.
Why don't you roll to hit?
Roll a D20 and add 5 for Pip Thistlewick.
D20 and add 5 for Pip Thistlewick.
Okay.
Slash R D 20.
D2.
Plus 5.
Plus 4, actually.
Sorry.
Plus 4.
Oh, I did a 5.
It doesn't matter, you missed.
Alright.
Sister Maela.
What does Sister Maela do?
She roll a D20 to see, and she's going to try to hit him with her mace.
Yes, roll a D20 and add 4.
Oh, that's it.
You roll.
No.
What did you do?
No, no, sorry.
No, I think I did a.
Yeah.
Okay, there we go.
You said rolling 20 plus 4.
Okay, that's a new way to roll a D20.
Alright.
So you manage, she swings her mace and hits him and does six points of damage.
He's like, all right.
Who is...
Yeah, it's your turn.
Zenvon, I presume you're going to try to walk up to him and attack him twice with your daggers?
Yes.
The dagger attack seems to be strong.
Alright.
Alright, remember, short sword and then dagger.
Oh, no.
A dagger first.
That is a miss.
Alright.
So a short sword next?
Yes.
Ooh, nice.
Nine points of damage.
Alright.
Okay, another question.
Like, the previous thing was 13, right?
The total damage from the dagger.
Yes.
Did that work, or was it a miss?
You see the number next to dagger?
Yes.
That was what you rolled to hit.
20 is the number I rolled to hit.
So if you look at, if you bring up, share your screen.
Yes.
Alright.
This number here.
Sorry.
Yes, yes, the piercing damage.
No, no, this number here, the one over here.
Yes, yes, yes.
That number here.
That was the roll you did to hit.
Okay.
His armor class is 17.
So that's clearly below 7.
7 is clearly below 17.
Okay, okay.
Right?
So you missed.
Oh, I see.
Okay.
The short sword has an armor class of 20, like so.
No, no, no.
So the way, so, no, no.
So if you go back to this thing, what happened is if you look at this, right, over here, if you click on the short sword, like put your mouse over the 20.
No, no.
Where do I have my red?
Yes, okay.
You see where it says 15 plus 5.
Yeah, that means that you rolled a 15.
And you add 5 for your 2-hit bonus.
See this number here?
Yes, okay.
Right?
And that gives you a 20.
Okay.
Right?
Does that follow?
Yes.
So what happened was you missed with the dagger and hit with a short sword.
Okay, okay.
Alright.
And so when you click on this, like just click when you click on this, just click on it just for now, just so you can see how it works.
Click where I did a circle?
No, no, not there.
That just.
Yeah.
Okay, well, that doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
When you roll over here, it just rolls to hit.
If you roll where the...
You see where the shortbow is?
Right.
Click there.
No, it's just.
There.
Now, that is...
Then it says you rolled.
That's the damage you rolled.
You see how it works, right?
Okay, okay, yeah, yeah.
Make sense?
Yes, yes, yes.
Alright.
So, yeah, so the first attack was a miss.
The second attack was a hit.
Okay.
Cool.
Alright.
Yes.
Alrighty.
Okay, Veyra of the blue candle will try to hit him with a firebolt again.
And she hits him.
Is he dead yet?
Uh let's see.
Yes, she kills him.
He dies.
Ah!
Victory stars.
What?
Yes, I'm presuming you're not the like shouting at the top of your lungs to attract attention.
Of course, yeah.
I've got to contain my exact.
Okay.
Let me see.
Alright.
Obligatory.
I don't know if you heard the victory music.
I faintly hear it, some music, but.
Okay, probably ignore.
Playing something.
Didn't work.
Anyway, doesn't matter.
Okay.
Alright, so you can look around to see if there's any treasure, which is always a good idea.
Oh, yes.
Let's scout this area for treasure, guys.
So you look over the dead bodies.
Collect points.
Unfortunately.
Unfortunately, they don't seem to have anything on them of any value.
Other than a javelin and a scimitar.
So I can take the weapons.
I'm going to take the javelin.
The javelin.
Can this guy handle the javelin?
Yes, he can.
No, I don't know if your guy can handle the javelin.
Right.
How can I see the weapons?
What we can.
If you, again, show your screen.
Yeah.
It's inventory.
Yep, yep.
Quick inventory.
So you see where it says add equipment?
Yes.
Click on that and look now.
And just take a second and type over here scimitar.
A javelin, rather.
A scimitar, whatever.
Alright, so if you click add.
And spelled scimitar, just the scimitar?
Just the scimitar.
Yes.
Equipment added.
Okay.
Right.
Javelin.
Okay.
I added both.
I guess Pip Thistlewick should take a javelin too.
So if the equipment is not.
I mean, if the guy cannot handle the equipment, we cannot add that same here.
No, you can add it, but if you go to, like, to use it, you won't have a proficiency bonus.
Oh, I see, okay.
So if you go to actions, go to actions.
Yeah, this is the actions.
Oh, you have to go to your equipment.
Go manage equipment.
Okay.
And then you've got to look for your javelin.
Scimitar.
Click on the scimitar.
And where it says equip.
Now you're equipped with it.
But I see the javelin as well.
So you go there, you equip it.
There.
It works.
Okay.
Yes, and then, well, hold on.
I don't know how this is where we're going to find out whether the PM agreed that this was a bug worth fixing.
Click on the go back to your actions.
Alright.
And
yeah, so you don't have proficiency with that, which is why you only have plus one to hit.
Oh, with javelin, yes, okay.
Right.
If you had proficiency, you would have plus five.
Okay, okay.
I think so.
Anyway.
Yes, your proficiency is a plus two, yes.
So you do not have you are not proficient with it.
Okay, but I can still use it.
Yes, but you use it a lot less effectively than other weapons.
And is it like a one-time thing, javelin?
Because, you know.
Well, you can use it either as a ranged weapon or a melee weapon.
Okay.
Alright, so you can either throw it or hold on or hold on to it.
And stabby, stabby.
And I can.
Once again, I'm sharing my screen.
It looks like I can increase the quantity here.
Like, you know.
It was saying 0.5 GP.
If I increase the cost, it says the big 4 power.
Yeah, I don't.
Okay, so here's something.
There's this concept in Dungeons and Dragons called encumbrance, which is how many things you can carry.
Okay, okay.
I don't play with it because I believe that Dungeons and Dragons should not be about accounting.
At the same time, if you're carrying 50,000 swords, I will say no.
Okay.
Yeah.
Alright, so, no, I'm not going to sit there and force you to count.
Some people play with counting the number of arrows you shoot.
Oh, interesting.
That's okay.
I don't.
To me, the game is about the game, not about sitting there and playing resource management games.
Other people, on the other hand, enjoy it and think that it adds to the game.
I'm just telling you what I don't do.
So.
Got it.
Got it?
Yes.
Alrighty.
Okay.
We have like five more minutes.
Great.
So we should add on another cliffhanger.
Do you want to keep...
Let's go a little bit further into the cavern.
Yes.
Okay.
Cliffhangers.
I love cliffhangers.
Yes.
Zenvon, you probably want to sneak in to see what's going on.
Sneak in.
Okay.
Sneak roll.
Yes.
Yeah.
Stealth roll.
Yes.
Turn stealth, stealth, stealth.
Stealth.
Yes.
What's the stealth?
Alright.
23.
What race are you?
Half-ling.
Okay.
Alright.
You managed to walk over here and notice three wolves.
We have a few.
You could keep walking if you want.
Okay.
Wait, do I see anything in the stealth on the side?
After the stealth roll?
No?
No, yes.
What you did was nobody saw you, so the wolves didn't notice you.
I see.
Okay.
So, yeah, I'll keep walking and exploring until because I have a stealth.
No, no.
Every time you move, you have to.
Every time you have to move.
Do I have to roll a stealth?
Yes.
Well, anytime somebody might notice you, you have to roll a stealth.
Alright.
Roll another stealth roll.
Okay.
Or rather, you arrive over here.
Which way do you want to go?
Left side.
Alright.
Roll a stealth roll.
Yeah.
Alright.
The main passage from this cavemouth thieves.
Steep stash.
Alright.
From this point on, you realize you will need either dark vision or a light source.
If you're carrying a light source, it's going to be kind of hard to walk stealthily, so you probably want to head back.
Okay, so I need a dark vision.
How do I get it?
Like, collect somewhere?
No, dark vision is an ability of ability.
How do I gain that?
No, no, no.
It's an ability of races.
Okay, so I have it already.
You either have it or you don't.
I mean, okay, where can I check that?
I think halflings don't have dark vision.
Okay.
But the good news is, Sister Maela, who's a dwarf, has it, and I think Veyra, who is a teetling, has it.
So that's the good news.
Okay, okay.
So Veyra also has a candle, the blue light candle.
Yes, so the problem with carrying a candle in the dark is that it's kind of hard to be stealthy when you're carrying a bright light.
Of course, yes, okay.
Alright.
Okay, man.
We'll stop here.
Okay.
Oh, okay.
I'm waiting for the cliffhanger.
Did I see anything?
Did I sense anything?
As you're standing there.
So, are you going up through here?
Are you going to try to go up there and just walk in the dark?
Yeah, I'm going to stay there.
Like, my friends are behind.
Well, your friends aren't far back, fine.
You're going to have to go get them back.
Yes, yes.
As you stand there, this passage is choked with rubble and blocked by steep slide.
As you move up to it, check out what's there.
I just thought that was a sound that you made.
You notice a giant coiled poisonous snake that right here.
So, as you go up there to check, what you suddenly hear is this hiss of a giant poisonous snake.
Okay.
You can see the snake?
I can see a semicircular red color thing.
I don't see the snake.
I think the map is not cleared in that part.
There is.
I see the snake, yes.
Alright, alright, cool.
So, yes, there's a giant snake that you just sort of walk up and you sort of look at it, and it kind of doesn't notice you.
Yes, right in your face.
But thanks to yourself, it hasn't noticed you yet.
Right, yes.
So, I slowly tiptoe back and yeah, that's the quick anchor.
Yes, yes, we stop there.
All right.
All right, man.
Take care.
I enjoyed this course of this.
Me too, me too.
Enjoy your weekend.
Thank you.
No problem.
You too.
Have a good one.
Bye-bye.